




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Priority Queues on Data Structures in C#</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Priority Queues on Data Structures in C#</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Heaps</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/heaps/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/heaps/index.html</guid>
      <description>Heaps A common structure for implementing a priority queue is known as a heap. A heap is a tree whose nodes contain elements with priorities that can be ordered. Furthermore, if the heap is nonempty, its root contains the maximum priority of any node in the heap, and each of its children is also a heap. Note that this implies that, in any subtree, the maximum priority is at the root.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leftist Heaps</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/leftist-heaps/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/leftist-heaps/index.html</guid>
      <description>Leftist Heaps One efficient way to complete the merge algorithm outlined in the previous section revolves around the concept of the null path length of a tree. For any tree t, null path length of t is defined to be $ 0 $ if t is empty, or one more than the minimum of the null path lengths of its children if t is nonempty. Another way to understand this concept is that it gives the minimum number of steps needed to get from the root to an empty subtree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huffman Trees</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/huffman-trees/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/huffman-trees/index.html</guid>
      <description>Huffman Trees In this section, we&amp;rsquo;ll consider an application of min-priority queues to the general problem of compressing files. Consider, for example, a plain text file like this copy of the U. S. Constitution . This file is encoded using UTF-8, the most common encoding for plain text files. The characters most commonly appearing in English-language text files are each encoded as one byte (i.e., eight bits) using this scheme. For example, in the text file referenced above, every character is encoded as a single byte (the first three bytes of the file are an optional code indicating that it is encoded in UTF-8 format).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>