




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trees on Data Structures in C#</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trees on Data Structures in C#</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Trees</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/intro/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/intro/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Trees A tree is a mathematical structure having a hierarchical nature. A tree may be empty, or it may consist of:
a root, and zero or more children, each of which is also a tree. Consider, for example, a folder (or directory) in a Windows file system. This folder and all its sub-folders form a tree &amp;mdash; the root of the tree is the folder itself, and its children are the folders directly contained within it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search Trees</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/bst/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/bst/index.html</guid>
      <description>Binary Search Trees We motivated our discussion of trees by expressing a need for a linked data structure that supports a binary search or something similar. We will present such a data structure - a binary search tree - in this section. While it will support efficient lookups, insertions, and deletions for many applications, we will see that there are cases in which it performs no better than a linked list.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AVL Trees</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/avl/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/avl/index.html</guid>
      <description>AVL Trees Up to this point, we haven&amp;rsquo;t addressed the performance of binary search trees. In considering this performance, let&amp;rsquo;s assume that the time needed to compare two keys is bounded by some fixed constant. The main reason we do this is that this cost doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on the number of keys in the tree; however, it may depend on the sizes of the keys, as, for example, if keys are strings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tries</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/tries/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/tries/index.html</guid>
      <description>Tries AVL trees give us an efficient mechanism for storage and retrieval, particularly if we need to be able to process the elements in order of their keys. However, there are special cases where we can achieve better performance. One of these special cases occurs when we need to store a list of words, as we might need in a word game, for example. For such applications, a trie provides for even more efficient storage and retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priority Queues</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/trees/priority-queues/index.html</guid>
      <description>Priority Queues Often we need a data structure that supports efficient storage of data items and their subsequent retrieval in order of some pre-determined priority. We have already seen two instances of such data structures: stacks and queues. With a stack, the later the item is stored, the higher its priority. With a queue, the earlier the item is stored, the higher its priority. More generally, we would like to be able to set priorities arbitrarily, in a way that may be unrelated to the order in which they were stored.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>