<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>strings and StringBuilders :: Data Structures in C#</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/strings/</link><description>strings and StringBuilders C# and .NET provide two data structures for representing sequences of characters - strings and StringBuilders. Each of these data structures has its own advantages and disadvantages. In this chapter, we will examine how these two types are used and implemented. In the process, we will note the tradeoffs involved in using one or the other.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/strings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>strings</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/strings/strings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/strings/strings/</guid><description>strings Instances of the string class are immutable sequences of characters. Because string is a class, it is a reference type. Because instances are immutable, once they are constructed, their contents cannot change. Note that this does not mean that string variables cannot change - we can assign a string variable s the value “abc” and later assign it the value “xyz”. These assignments simply assign to s references to different instances of the string class. What immutability does mean is that there is no way to change any of the characters in either of these instances (i.e., in either “abc” or “xyz”). As a result, it is safe to copy a string by simply assigning the value of one string variable to another; for example, if s is a string variable, we can write:</description></item><item><title>StringBuilders</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/strings/stringbuilders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/strings/stringbuilders/</guid><description>StringBuilders In the previous section, we saw that building large strings from small pieces by concatenating them together is very inefficient. This inefficiency is due to the fact that strings are immutable. In order to overcome the inefficiency of concatenation, we need an alternative data structure that we can modify. The StringBuilder class fills this need.
Like strings, StringBuilders implement sequences of characters, but the contents of StringBuilders can be changed. The StringBuilder class has six constructors. The simplest StringBuilder constructor takes no parameters and constructs an empty StringBuilder — i.e., a StringBuilder containing no characters:</description></item><item><title>Implementation of StringBuilders</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/strings/stringbuilder-impl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/strings/stringbuilder-impl/</guid><description>Implementation of StringBuilders In this section, we will examine some of the implementation details of the StringBuilder class. There are several reasons for doing this. First, by examining these details, we can begin to understand why a StringBuilder is so much more efficient than a string when it comes to building long strings a character at a time. Second, by studying implementations of data structures, we can learn techniques that might be useful to us if we need to build our own data structures. Finally, a computing professional who better understands the underlying software will be better equipped to use that software effectively.</description></item></channel></rss>