<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linked Lists :: Data Structures in C#</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/linked-lists/</link><description>Linked Lists Using arrays to implement data structures has performance advantages in some cases, but this technique has its limitations. With this chapter, we begin a study of data structures that use reference types in a powerful way. Rather than forming sequences by placing data items in adjacent cells of an array, we instead use references to chain data elements together in a sequence. For some applications, this ends up being more efficient than using an array. As we will see in a later chapter, this chaining technique can be further exploited to link data items in a hierarchical way, providing even more flexible and efficient access.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/linked-lists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Linked Lists</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/linked-lists/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/linked-lists/intro/</guid><description>Introduction to Linked Lists To build a linked list, we first need to define a simple class, which we will call LinkedListCell&lt;T>. Instances of this class will be the individual building blocks that we will chain together to form linked lists. T will be the type of the data item we will store in each cell - i.e., the type of the data items that we will store in the linked list.</description></item><item><title>Implementing Stacks and Queues with Linked Lists</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/linked-lists/stacks-queues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/linked-lists/stacks-queues/</guid><description>Implementing Stacks and Queues with Linked Lists Because linked lists store data elements in linear sequences, they can be used to give alternative implementations of stacks and queues. One advantage to using linked lists is that we don’t have to worry about filling up something like an array - we can just keep allocating cells as long as we need to (unless we run out of memory).
Implementing a stack using a linked list is particularly easy because all accesses to a stack are at the top. One end of a linked list, the beginning, is always directly accessible. We should therefore arrange the elements so that the top element of the stack is at the beginning of the linked list, and the bottom element of the stack is at the end of the linked list. We can represent an empty stack with null.</description></item><item><title>Finding Prime Numbers</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/linked-lists/sieve-eratosthenes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cis300/linked-lists/sieve-eratosthenes/</guid><description>Finding Prime Numbers An integer greater than $ 1 $ is said to be prime if it is not divisible by any positive integers other than itself and $ 1 $. Thus, $ 2 $, $ 3 $, and $ 5 $ are prime, but not $ 1 $ (it is not greater than $ 1 $) or $ 4 $ (it is divisible by $ 2 $). Because every integer is divisible by itself and $ 1 $, we will call any other positive factors nontrivial factors; thus, a prime number is an integer greater than $ 1 $ that has no nontrivial factors. The study of prime numbers dates back to at least the third century BC. One of the earliest known algorithms finds all prime numbers less than a given integer $ n $. This algorithm is known as the Sieve of Eratosthenes, and is attributed to the Greek mathematician Eratosthenes of Cyrene (c. 276 BC - c. 194 BC).</description></item></channel></rss>