




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dialogs on Data Structures in C#</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/io/dialogs/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dialogs on Data Structures in C#</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/io/dialogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MessageBoxes</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/io/dialogs/message-boxes/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/io/dialogs/message-boxes/index.html</guid>
      <description>Message Boxes The MessageBox class (found in the System.Windows.Forms namespace) provides a simple mechanism for displaying a message and obtaining one of a few simple responses from the user. The most common usage of a MessageBox is to call one of its various Show methods, each of which is static . The simplest Show method takes a string as its only parameter. The method then displays this string in a modal dialog containing an &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>File Dialogs</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/io/dialogs/file-dialogs/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/io/dialogs/file-dialogs/index.html</guid>
      <description>File Dialogs The System.Windows.Forms namespace contains two other classes that implement modal dialogs for obtaining file names from the user. These classes are OpenFileDialog , which is designed to obtain the name of a file to read, and SaveFileDialog , which is designed to obtain the name of a file to write. Because we often need to obtain the name of a file prior to doing file I/O, it is appropriate to consider these classes now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Dialogs</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/io/dialogs/custom/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis300/io/dialogs/custom/index.html</guid>
      <description>Custom Dialogs While the dialogs provided by the .NET Framework are useful in a variety of applications, there are times when we need to be able to design our own special-purpose dialog to obtain specific information from the user. This section outlines how Visual Studio® can be used to build such a dialog.
Let&amp;rsquo;s begin by considering a simple example. Suppose we are building an application that needs a dialog to obtain from the user the following pieces of information:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>